<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[warizz.io]]></title><description><![CDATA[All public info of a man named Warizz]]></description><link>warizz.io</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 06:33:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Positive Constructive Feedback]]></title><description><![CDATA[In  Mission To The Moon, 236th episode  somebody asked about ‘direct feedback’ which is very interesting because it can be use for both work…]]></description><link>warizz.io/positive-constructive-feedback/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">warizz.io/positive-constructive-feedback/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/missiontothemoon/ep-236-9-2561&quot;&gt;Mission To The Moon, 236th episode&lt;/a&gt; somebody asked about ‘direct feedback’ which is very interesting because it can be use for both work and life. There are 4 types of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative and destructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative and constructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positive and destructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positive and constructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Destructive is a feedback that only mean to make listeners feel bad, for example “You write bad code, stop doing it”, this doesn’t give any clues why it is bad or how to improve it. So constructive way is to give “what”, “why” and “how”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know that there are no benefits of negative destructive feedback (may be a little satisfaction to the giver) and receivers will also feel defeated or even get angry, so we should avoid it if possible. Even though we sometimes have to give a negative feedback even in a constructive way, we should carefully think about how to make the negative part softer. If you found out that it is impossible to give constructive feedback, it may be means that you only want to destroy the listeners and it is better to not speak it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In life outside of work is a lot harder, especially family members or close friends, so many people (included me) keep their mouth shut to avoid the fight. So positive + constructive is a good way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s try to solve this situation just to practice, if you found out that your partner didn’t clean dishes properly (some still have stain), how will you give a positive constructive feedback? I can start with the positive “Hey, how nice of you clean all the dishes” then “but I think we have to change current dishwashing soap because it still leaves some mark on them” (ummm I don’t think this is constructive, it just detour destructive) or try “Next time we finished our food, I think I will help you roughly wash dishes first so it will be easier when you come to finish them later, not leaving hard stain like this time” (constructive by using yourself as bait)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think giving good feedback can be practiced, the key is to keep in mind that we have to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;วันนี้ได้ฟัง &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/missiontothemoon/ep-236-9-2561&quot;&gt;Mission To The Moon episode ที่ 236&lt;/a&gt; มีคนถามเรื่อง direct feedback น่าสนใจดี เพราะมันจะนำไปใช้ได้ทั้งเรื่องงานและชีวิตประจำวัน สรุปได้คร่าวๆว่า มันมีอยู่ 4 แบบ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative and destructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative and constructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positive and destructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positive and constructive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;negative และ positive ก็คือการติและชม destructive ก็คือการตำหนิที่ไม่ได้เสนอแนะแนวทาง หรือช่วยเหลือผู้ฟังให้พัฒนาตัวเองขึ้นมาได้ เช่น ทีมลีดตำหนิลูกทีมว่า เขียนโค้ดแย่มาก โดยไม่ให้เหตุผล หรือวิธีการเขียนที่ดีกว่า ส่วน constructive ก็คือการ บอกลูกทีมว่า เขียนแบบนี้สิ มันดีกว่า เพราะอ่านง่าย และมี performance ที่ดีกว่า พร้อมให้ตัวอย่าง&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;อย่างที่รู้กันว่า negative และ destructive นั้นนอกจากจะไม่ก่อให้เกิดประโยชน์กับใครแล้ว (อาจจะสะใจแก่ผู้พูด) ยังก่อผลลบแก่ผู้ฟังอีก เพราะฉะนั้นถ้าเป็นไปได้ก็ควรหลีกเลี่ยง และคิดเยอะๆ ก่อนพูดทุกครั้ง negative + constructive คิดว่า บางครั้งก็เลี่ยงไม่ได้ ถ้าจำเป็นต้องตำหนิจริงๆ ก็ต้องหาวิธีพูดให้นิ่มนวลที่สุด ถ้าพบว่าไม่สามารถคิด constructive feedback ก็แสดงว่า คุณอาจแค่ทำเพื่อความสะใจของตัวเองเท่านั้น และยกเลิกที่จะพูดออกไปเสีย&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;การให้ feedback ในชีวิตประจำวันนั้นยากกว่าในที่ทำงานมาก เพราะถ้าเป็นคนในครอบครัว หรือแม้แต่เพื่อน เรายิ่งต้องระวังเรื่องการไปกระทบจิตใจคนฟัง คนจำนวนมาก(รวมถึงตัวผมเองด้วย) เลือกที่จะไม่เตือนหรือตำหนิในบางเรื่อง เพื่อหลีกเลี่ยงการพิพาท การให้ feedback ที่เป็น positive และ constructive จึงเป็นการแก้ปัญหาที่ดี&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ลองคิดเล่นๆว่า ถ้าเราเจอคราบอาหารบนจานชามที่แฟนล้างไว้ การให้ positive + constructive feedback ก็ควรจะเป็นอย่างไรได้บ้าง เท่าที่ผมพอจะนึกได้คือ เธอน่ารักมาก อุตส่าห์ล้างจานให้ (เริ่มด้วย positive) แต่สงสัยน้ำยาล้างจานจะไม่ค่อยดี เพราะมันยังเหลือคราบอยู่หน่อยนึงตรงนี้ (ไม่ค่อย constructive สักเท่าไหร่ เหมือนเป็น destructive แบบอ้อมๆ มากกว่า) หรือ คราวหน้าหลังกินเสร็จเดี๋ยวเราเอาฟองน้ำล้างคร่าวๆให้ก่อนรอบนึง เวลาแฟนมาล้างทีหลังจะได้ล้างง่ายๆ ไม่เหลือคราบ (เป็นการ constructive อ้อมๆ โดยเอาตัวเองเข้าแลก)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;การให้ความเห็นที่ดีนั้นต้องใช้ทั้งศาสตร์และศิลป์พอสมควร แต่ผมว่าเรื่องพวกนี้นั้นฝึกได้ ขอแค่ต้องพึงระลึกไว้เสมอ&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Random thought: on building a house]]></title><description><![CDATA[Even though having a condominium is the best answer right now because of work place and short commute time but the dream of owning a house…]]></description><link>warizz.io/random-thought-on-building-a-house/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">warizz.io/random-thought-on-building-a-house/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Even though having a condominium is the best answer right now because of work place and short commute time but the dream of owning a house that has the design I like is still exist. I never think of living in a crowded city the whole life anyway. Roughly plan is after I paid all the mortgage — estimation is 10 to 15 years — I will have a house outside of town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 year is very loooong time. If we learn something and do it regularly throughout the period, we can be a professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Architecture is interesting, if you want a house that fit your desire, you have to build it yourself instead of buying a completed one. You don’t have to do it yourself entirely, just to be able to deal with house contractors is a worth to try, able to design interior or exterior is a plus. You can finish a college and then have 6 years professional experience in this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ถึงคอนโดจะเป็นคำตอบที่ดีที่สุดในตอนนี้ เพราะทำงานในเมืองสะดวกเดินทาง แต่ความไฝ่ฝันจะมีบ้านเป็นของตัวเอง และดีไซน์แบบที่ชอบ ก็ยังมีอยู่ และก็ไม่ได้คิดจะอยู่ในเมืองไปตลอดชีวิตอยู่แล้ว แพลนที่คิดไว้เล่นๆก็คือ พอผ่อนคอนโดปัจจุบันหมด —น่าจะสัก ๑๐ ถึง ๑๕ ปี — ก็จะเริ่มไปหาที่สร้างบ้าน นอกเมือง&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;๑๕ ปีนี้มันนานมากนะ เป็นระยะเวลาที่ถ้าเราเริ่มต้นเรียนรู้อะไรสักอย่าง แล้วทำมันไปเรื่อยๆ ตลอด อย่างสม่ำเสมอ เราสามารถกลายเป็นผู้เชี่ยวชาญได้เลย  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;เรียนรู้เรื่องสถาปัตยกรรม ก็น่าสนใจ ถ้าอยากได้บ้านที่มีดีไซน์เป็นของตัวเอง ก็ต้องสร้างขึ้นจากศูนย์ ไม่ถึงกับต้องสร้างเองทุกอย่างหรอก แต่แค่มีความรู้ที่จะไปตรวจงานผู้รับเหมาได้ ก็คุ้มค่าแล้ว นี่ถ้าบังเอิญไปได้ดี สามารถออกแบบภายใน ภายนอกได้เอง ก็จะยิ่งมีประโยชน์, ๑๐ ปี สามารถเรียนจบมหาวิทยาลัย และมีประสบการณ์ทำงานอีก ๖ ปีเลยนะ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m on a practice of writing in English, if you reader found any grammatical errors please help point it out will be very appreciated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On dealing with failures]]></title><description><![CDATA[Failure is a good thing if you handle it well. What — note it down, every single one of them should be listed. Why — find the root cause…]]></description><link>warizz.io/on-dealing-with-failures/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">warizz.io/on-dealing-with-failures/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Failure is a good thing if you handle it well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What — note it down, every single one of them should be listed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why — find the root cause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How — try to think about how to prevent it to happen again in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is to learn from your mistake, embrace it. What doesn’t kill you, makes you stronger (yeah, super cliché but true).&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On commute]]></title><description><![CDATA[Listening is the best thing I can think of right now while I’m on commute. Podcast, audio book (Youtube sometimes but annoying when you must…]]></description><link>warizz.io/on-commute/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">warizz.io/on-commute/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Listening is the best thing I can think of right now while I’m on commute. Podcast, audio book (Youtube sometimes but annoying when you must turn on the screen while playing it) have lots of good content to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audio book — I’m using Audible, with monthly subscription you get a credit to buy a free book every month. I wish Thai publishers have something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podcast — Here’s the list. I think you can search their name on any podcast app you’re using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE STANDARD podcast&lt;/strong&gt; (Thai) — they have lots of topics from financial to running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mission the moon&lt;/strong&gt; (Thai) — life, work and entrepreneurship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;React podcast&lt;/strong&gt; — programming, React specifically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Old App&lt;/strong&gt; — programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase play back speed so you can listen more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise cancellation headphone is perfect on public transport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always bring a book with you, in some situation that you can not use your headphone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Goals: 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m turning 35 next year, it passed half life already so I should step forward carefully. Pick what’s really matters and prioritize them, be…]]></description><link>warizz.io/goals-2019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">warizz.io/goals-2019/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m turning 35 next year, it passed half life already so I should step forward carefully. Pick what’s really matters and prioritize them, be more focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should be improved based on my metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Go&lt;/code&gt; — personal interested, Its philosophy feels minimalistic to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/code&gt; — this can improve my workflow when we have so many projects working together these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;data science&lt;/code&gt;— I think programming world going toward this way, building data-based machine to help us work better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emotionless&lt;/strong&gt;, to be specific, no angry. This can be tracked by note down every time I get angry. Goal is to make them as less as possible. It will be good to any person around me especially my girl friend that I spend most of the time with. (love you xo xo).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climb better&lt;/strong&gt;— 20 v4s, 20 6a, 5 v5s. Every time I sent a target route I took a picture then saved it to Google Photos album named by level. Ultimate goal (2–3 years plan) is to climb &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/7DCiOy6Dxe8&quot;&gt;somewhere magnificent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At least a marathon&lt;/strong&gt; — I finished it once (5.5 hours) long time ago. Actually this was set by my girl friend, it is good to have any common goal together and climbing needs both strength and endurance so working this long running activity should help improve it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lose weight&lt;/strong&gt; — ideal is to be as lean as possible. The target is 65kg (currently 75). Yeah this leads to improvement of my climbing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More writing, more drawing&lt;/strong&gt; — 100 articles, 3 days per 1 post seems not hard at all. How about drawing? I’m planing to have some visual essays about my (wannabe) minimalistic life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn music&lt;/strong&gt;-I used to practice guitar but it never go anywhere. I’m taking it seriously this time by taking a course to learn its fundamental. The target instrument may be guitar, drum or piano.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On measuring work]]></title><description><![CDATA[tl;dr  efficiency  and  meaningfulness . Efficiency There are 2 factors for evaluation,  time  and  money . Easiest way to improve is…]]></description><link>warizz.io/on-measuring-work/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">warizz.io/on-measuring-work/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;tl;dr &lt;strong&gt;efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;meaningfulness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Efficiency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 2 factors for evaluation, &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;. Easiest way to improve is growing the value of money/time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meaningfulness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about it for couple of months, and got a rough conclusion that &lt;strong&gt;I care about how many people using my work&lt;/strong&gt; so I will use it as a indicator, google analytics can help you about this. I don’t think this is the best way to measure how meaningful of a work and I will continue finding it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Working with legacy code: environment variables]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hard-coded environment variables make deployment to another environment very hard because we have to look into the code to find out where…]]></description><link>warizz.io/working-with-legacy-code-environment-variables/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">warizz.io/working-with-legacy-code-environment-variables/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hard-coded environment variables make deployment to another environment very hard because we have to look into the code to find out where are all the conditions. It is also not secure because we have to put some API key into the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;/code&gt; we used to define environment variables like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; globalVars &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;DefinePlugin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;GRAPH_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;API_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;NODE_ENV&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;production&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  globalVars &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;DefinePlugin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;GRAPH_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;API_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;  
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;NODE_ENV&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;local&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  globalVars &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;DefinePlugin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;GRAPH_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;API_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we need to have another environment like &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;test&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;staging&lt;/code&gt; we have add more if conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;NODE_ENV&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;local&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  globalVars &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;DefinePlugin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;GRAPH_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;API_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;some-url&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;NODE_ENV&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;test&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;NODE_ENV&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;staging&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only in &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;/code&gt; config, we have them all over the places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// server.js&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; hostname &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;SERVER_TYPE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;production&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;www.theasia.com&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;www.theasiadev.com&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;SERVER_TYPE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;production&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;SERVER_TYPE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;development&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;    
  app&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;use&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;forceDomain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; hostname&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; protocol&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;https&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;process.env&lt;/code&gt; , so we can remove all if conditions then the code looks a lot simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// webpack.config.js&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; globalVars &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;webpack&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;DefinePlugin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;GRAPH_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;GRAPH_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;API_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;API_SERVER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// server.js&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; hostname &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; process&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;env&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token constant&quot;&gt;HOSTNAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;hostname&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;    
  app&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;use&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;forceDomain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; hostname&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; protocol&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;https&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many ways to define &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;process.env&lt;/code&gt;, on local machine, we use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/dotenv&quot;&gt;dotenv&lt;/a&gt; to load all variables from &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file. On &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/code&gt;, we use &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.jenkins.io/display/JENKINS/EnvInject+Plugin&quot;&gt;EnvInject Plugin&lt;/a&gt;. On AWS, it will base on which kind of server you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on, when we need to have another server, we can just deploy the app to new environment then change &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;process.env&lt;/code&gt;, no need any new git commit.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>